<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<section xml:id="api_ua_ns"
      xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      version="5.0" xml:lang="en">

  <title>API between the User Agent and the Notification Server</title>
  <para>
    With this API the client device is able to register his applications and
    itself into the selected notification server.
  </para>
  <para>
    This API isn't yet standarised, anyway the one explained here is an 
    on working proposal.
  </para>
  <para>
    The UA-NS API is divided in two transport protocols:
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        HTTP API: Through the HTTP transport protocol the NS will deliver
        some information about server status.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        WebSocket API: This is the most important one since all the
        communications with the NS SHALL be driven through this API.
        <para>
          On future releases will be supported another channels as Long-Polling
          solutions in order to cover devices which don't support Web Sockets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section>
      <title>HTTP API</title>
      <para>
        This channel only offers one method to get server information.
      </para>
      <section>
        <title>about</title>
        <para>
          This method responds an HTML page with general information about the
          running server like number of connections, number of process running...
        </para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>WebSocket API</title>
      <para>
        Through this channel the device will register itself, his applications,
        and also will be used to deliver PUSH notifications
      </para>
      <para>
        The websocket API supports multiple subprotocols identified each one
        with it's name:
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            push-notification
            <para>
              Simple protocol defined by Mozilla and Telefonica and described
              here:
              <link xlink:href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/WebAPI/SimplePush/Protocol">
                [https://wiki.mozilla.org/WebAPI/SimplePush/Protocol]
              </link>.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            push-notification-binary
            <para>
              Binary version of the push-notification protocol
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            push-extended-notification
            <para>
              Telefonica extended solution which provides more functionalities
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      <xi:include href="api_ua_ns_websocket_pushnotification.xml" />
      <xi:include href="api_ua_ns_websocket_pushnotification_binary.xml" />
      <xi:include href="api_ua_ns_websocket_extendedpushnotification.xml" />
    </section>
  </para>
</section>
