<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="future"
      xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      version="5.0" xml:lang="en">

  <title>Future ideas for next releases</title>
  <para>
    The following sections will point out future ideas to be developed in next
    server releases.
  </para>
  <section xml:id="future_ipv6">
    <title>IPv6 support</title>
    <para></para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="future_enque">
    <title>Enque low priority messages</title>
    <para>
      Enque low priority notifications which will be sent in a common
      connection, this will consider the TTL of the message.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="future_backuppings">
    <title>Backup pings</title>
    <para>
      If the client is not notified after some time, it will connect to the
      server and check if some message is pending to be delivered.
    </para>
    <para>
      If the server had messages for the client, an alarm should be fired,
      since some issue happened on the wakeup platform.
    </para>
    <para>
      In order to reduce network signalling, this PING should be only be
      shotted when a network connection had been done by any other application
      on the handset.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="future_wappush">
    <title>WAP Push</title>
    <para>
      Use WAP Push to wake up handsets. The MSISDN will be retrieved by the
      central server after an integration with the carrier.
    </para>
    <para>
      Because privacy reasons, the MSISND won't be shared with 3rd. party
      systems.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="future_abuse">
    <title>Abuse control</title>
    <para>
      Add abuse control on the external APIs
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="future_multiplenetworks">
    <title>Support multiple subnetworks</title>
    <para>
      Many carriers have more than one private network since the have more
      smartphones than the class A segment.
    </para>
    <para>
      Also, M2M solutions normally have their own private subnetwork.
    </para>
    <para>
      The Notification Server shall be well integrated on multiple subnetworks
      carriers.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="future_delivercontrol">
    <title>Increase delivery controls</title>
    <para>
      Add support on AS API to know the delivery status of the messages.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="future_presence">
    <title>Presence</title>
    <para>
      Offer a presence API to AS.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="future_delegated">
    <title>Support delegated modes and HUB systems</title>
    <para>
      Some carriers consider that multiple notification platforms should be
      interconnected between them.
    </para>
    <para>
      <imagedata fileref="resources/seqdiags/delegatedmode_simplified.png" align="center" width="5in" />
    </para>
  </section>

</chapter>
